you might be wondering if you have the
right background to do well in the class
now to be honest I find it really hard
to predict you students are always full
of surprises no amount of staring in
your GPAs or GRE scores has ever helped
me much and figuring out which of you
will be the brilliant rebel that changes
the field forever in the immortal words
of the prisoner you are not a number
you're a free man or woman anyway i hope
the following readiness survey will help
you get a sense of where you stand
here's how it's going to work you will
see a series of questions that cover the
math and CS 101 material that I think
you should feel comfortable with in
order to do well in the class try
working them out on your own pencil and
paper now if you don't know how to
approach a question right away don't
give up I fully expect that you might
need to go look something up in order to
refresh your memory on ways to approach
a given problem now when you think
you've got an answer or you feel like
you're really stuck take a look at the
solution that follows each question even
if you didn't get the right answer as
long as the solution makes sense and you
stay dedicated to the course it will
probably just be a matter of filling in
some gaps here and there on the other
hand if you still feel really
uncomfortable even after looking at the
solution then I would encourage you to
reconsider whether it might suck up a
lot of your time to get caught up on the
course okay so those are the ground
rules good luck and I hope to see you on
the other side of hell
you